# **HELEN GREER ANTELL**

215 Milbank Avenue, West Unit, Greenwich, CT 06830 hga24@cornell.edu | (203) 517-5533

June 22, 2019

Dr. Laurie Marker Director Cheetah Conservation Fund P.O. Box 1755 Otjiwarongo, Namibia

Dear Dr. Marker,

I am writing to you in regard to the internship opportunity at Cheetah Conservation Fund for this August 2019. I know you have been in contact with my mother, Lisa Antell, as she has told me so much about your operations in Namibia. As a Biology and Society major at Cornell University, I am very excited for the opportunity to apply for this position.

In completing my junior year at Cornell, I pursued a concentration in Evolution and Ecology within my major. My cumulative GPA over the course of my college experience is a 3.67, though this does not include my grades for courses taken while abroad at the University of New South Wales in Sydney, Australia. If chosen for this internship, I would gladly accept all the responsibilities associated with the position. I understand that I will likely work in various areas of the organization, and am particularly interested in the Bushblok and guard dog projects.

I first discovered my passion for ecology and sustainability during the summer of 2014 while studying at The Island School on the Bahamian island of Eleuthera. Since then, I have expressed academic interest in a variety of courses pertaining to these interests, such as Neurobiology and Behavior, Climate Change and Food Security, Plant Biodiversity, and more. I have not only enjoyed my time taking these courses, but I have also excelled in them due to my considerable enthusiasm for the topics they covered.

I am very glad to be applying for Cheetah Conservation Fund's internship in light of my interests and how they align with your goals and motivations. I would be delighted to have the opportunity for a personal interview. Please accept my résumé and feel free to contact me at your earliest convenience. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely, Helen Antell

# **HELEN GREER ANTELL**

215 Milbank Avenue, West Unit, Greenwich, CT 06830 hga24@cornell.edu | (203) 517-5533

#### **EDUCATION**

### **CORNELL UNIVERSITY, College of Arts and Sciences**

Bachelor of Arts

Ithaca, NY Class of 2020

Major in Biology and Society, Minor in Business

- Cumulative GPA: 3.67
- Dean's List, Fall 2017

#### THE LAWRENCEVILLE SCHOOL

Lawrenceville, NJ

High School Diploma

• Cumulative GPA: 3.65

• High Honors, Spring 2015 – Spring 2016

Counselor and Certified Waterfront Lifeguard

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **CAMP MERRIWOOD**

Orford, NH

**Class of 2016** 

Summer 2017

Mentored girls ages 8-15

• Instructed campers in swim and dance

• Assisted the Waterfront Director in assessing swim levels and training camper lifeguards

# GREENWICH COUNTRY DAY SCHOOL

Greenwich, CT

Assistant Dance Instructor

• Provided assistance in leading class as well as guiding and mentoring students

• Choreographed for the girls' final performance at the end of the dance intensive

### **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

# DELTA GAMMA, CHI CHAPTER

Ithaca, NY

2015 - 2016

Philanthropy

Fundraised for Service for Sight

Coached teams in Anchor Slam and Anchor Jam competitions

#### ASPCA AFFILIATED CLUB

Princeton, NJ 2014 – 2016

2017 - Present

Volunteer

Volunteer

Assisted at SAVE, A Friend to Homeless Animals, a local Princeton animal shelter

• Filed paperwork, cleaned cages, and walked dogs

## THE LAWRENCEVILLE SCHOOL SUMMER CAMP

Lawrenceville, NJ

Summer 2016

Volunteer Counselor

Mentored low-income children ages 7-12

• Taught swim lessons, played sports, and facilitated games and events

## THE ISLAND SCHOOL

Eleuthera, Bahamas

Summer 2014

Mentored local middle school children

• Successfully designed ecologically minded plots of land

#### **EXTRACURRICULARS**

Director of Funds

# **DELTA GAMMA, CHI CHAPTER**

Ithaca, NY

2017 - 2018

Accounting of chapter fees and activities from an annual budget of \$85,000

• Participate in meetings, activities, and philanthropy events

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Skills: Microsoft Office Suite, Elementary Spanish

Interests: Community Service, Coral Reef Ecology, SCUBA Diving, Travel, Reading, Ballet